journaldev.com 2019-06-04

# Privacy Policy - JournalDev

**Who we are**  
Our website address is: https://www.journaldev.com.

### What personal data we collect and why we collect it

 **Comments**  
When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

 **Media**  
If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

 **Contact forms, Cookies**  
If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

 **Embedded content from other websites**  
Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Caching

This site utilizes caching in order to facilitate a faster response time and better user experience. Caching potentially stores a duplicate copy of every web page that is on display on this site. All cache files are temporary and are never accessed by any third party, except as necessary to obtain technical support from the cache plugin vendor. Cache files expire on a schedule set by the site administrator, but may easily be purged by the admin before their natural expiration, if necessary.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics to track traffic, we don’t hold any data at our servers.

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

 **What rights you have over your data**

If you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

We don’t send your data to anybody else. However, when commenting third-party service is used for spam filtering.

 **Disclaimer**

The contents of this report are based on information generally available to the public from sources believed to be reliable. No representation is made that it is timely, accurate or complete. JournalDev has taken due care and caution in compilation of data as this has been obtained from various sources including which it considers reliable and first hand. However, JournalDev does not guarantee the accuracy, adequacy or completeness of any information and it is not responsible for any errors or omissions or for the results obtained from the use of such information and especially states that it has no financial liability whatsoever to the subscribers/users of this report. The information herein, together with all estimates and forecasts, can change without notice.

This report does not purport to be a solicitation of any advice pertaining to trade and business and readers are advised to consult experts or study/evaluate individual business prospectus and other relevant legal documents before taking any decisions based on information provided in the site. Neither JournalDev nor its Editors or Authors accept any liability whatsoever nor do they accept responsibility for any financial consequences arising from the use of the research or information provided herein.

 **Privacy Policy**  
We understand the importance of your privacy as a visitor to this website. We want you to understand how the information you may provide will be used. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested.

 **Information collected**  
[JournalDev](https://www.journaldev.com/) does not collect personal information about you except for the information that you voluntarily provide. We may collect usage information of our site to analyze interest in content and to provide advertisers information on an aggregate basis. No personally identifiable information will be shared with third-party advertising companies.

 **Community**  
When using our online community functions, your user ID, which defaults to your email address, will identify you. We encourage our users to select a unique user ID to avoid providing your email address to other users and third parties. Failure to use this feature to select a unique user ID may result in other users or third parties sending you unsolicited email.

 **Google Adsense and the DoubleClick DART Cookie**  
Google, as a third party advertisement vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site. The use of DART cookies by Google enables them to serve adverts to visitors that are based on their visits to this website as well as other sites on the internet.

To opt out of the DART cookies you may visit the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL [http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) Tracking of users through the DART cookie mechanisms are subject to Google’s own privacy policies.

Other Third Party ad servers or ad networks may also use cookies to track users activities on this website to measure advertisement effectiveness and other reasons that will be provided in their own privacy policies, JournalDev has no access or control over these cookies that may be used by third party advertisers.

 **Links to third party Websites**  
We have included links on this site for your use and reference. We are not responsible for the privacy policies on these websites. You should be aware that the privacy policies of these sites may differ from our own.

 **Changes to this Privacy Statement**  
The contents of this statement may be altered at any time, at our discretion.

If you have any questions regarding the privacy policy of JournalDev then you may contact me through the contact form on About page.

Best Regards,  
The [JournalDev](https://www.journaldev.com/) Team
